Wright Patman collection, Inclusive: 1955-1976, Bulk: 1961-1976
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials
Wright Patman collection
Inclusive: 1955-1976, Bulk: 1961-1976
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials http://www.baylor.edu/lib/bcpm/
57
Donor, Unknown
1 document box
A collection of materials pertaining to Congressman Wright Patman who represented Texas’s 1st District from 1929 until his death in office, March 1976.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Wright Patman was born at Patman's Switch, Cass County, TX, on August 6, 1893. He graduated from Hughes Springs High School in 1912, and Cumberland University, Lebanon, TN, in 1916. He was assistant county attorney of Cass County from 1916-1917, when he joined the US Army as a private and machine-gun officer during World War I.
Patman served in the Texas State House of Representatives from 1924-1929, when he was elected as a Democrat to the 71st Congress. He served the 1st Congressional District from 1929 until his death on March 4, 1976.
Scope and Content
The collection is comprised of a small amount of campaign items, correspondence sent to constituents by Patman’s administrative assistant after the death of the congressman. A list of bills introduced by Patman from 1929-1970, which was appears to be compiled at the same time, is included along with a relatively small number of Patman’s weekly letters which were published in local papers or mailed to constituents. The current arrangement is in four series: Campaign, Correspondence, Legislative, and Press.
Arrangement
Prior to this finding aid, the collection contained materials from other Poage collections. Although provenance is unclear, it may be this collection was part of the papers of Patman’s successor Sam B. Hall, and was removed to make an artificial collection. The current arrangement is in four series: Campaign, Correspondence, Legislative, and Press.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the W. R. Poage Legislative Library in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 57. Acquired 0-00-00
Related Resources
Related references
"PATMAN, Wright." Biographical Directory of the United States Congress. Accessed December 13, 2018.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Patman, Wright, 1893-1976.
Subjects (Organizations)
United States. Congress -- Constituent communication.; United States. Congress. House.
Places
Texas -- Politics and government -- 1929-1976.
Subjects
Political campaigns -- Texas.; Politicians -- Texas.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Legislative materials.; Newsletters.
- Campaign, 1955-1975; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  The Campaign series is comprised of one folder containing correspondence, 1972 election results by county, and Patman’s platform for the 1975 election. Although two pieces are from 1955 and 1962, the bulk of the items are from the 1970s. This series is in good condition.
  - General, 1955-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1976 March-June; 2
  The Correspondence series contains outgoing mail written to constituents after the death of Congressman Patman, explaining that their concerns would be passed on to his successor. This series is in good condition.
  Arrangement
  .
  - March, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - April (1 of 2), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - April (2 of 2), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - May-June, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Legislative, circa 1975; 3
  The Legislative series contains a listing, by Congress, of the bills introduced by Patman from the 71st to the 91st Congresses. The bill number, date of introduction, title, and all resolutions are included. This series is in good condition.
  - Introduced Bills by Congress, 71st-84th (1929-1956), circa 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Introduced Bills by Congress, 85th-91st (1957-1970), circa 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Press, 1961-1962, 1971-1976; 4
  The Press series contains a general file with press releases, news clippings, and other information of interest to constituents. The newsletter file contains 92 of Patman’s “Weekly Letters” arranged chronologically. This series is in good condition.
  - General, 1962-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, 1961-1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)